Andrew Bielecki

(401) 556-3079 | ambielecki@gmail.com | www.andrewbielecki.me | 5 Island Hill Ave #302, Malden, MA 02148

Summary

I spent ten years after graduating university in the Biotechnology field working in Biochemistry setting up screening assays for small molecule enzymatic inhibitors. This allowed me to grow skills in robotics programming, data analysis and general problem solving. After taking courses at Harvard Extension, where I am currently a Masters Candidate, I began a new career as a Software Engineer working at Purch, mainly with PHP based properties built on the Symfony and Yii frameworks. My current role at MobileFuse involves helping to maintain and add features to an internal dashboard written in Laravel, along with launching a new project for processing data, ingesting data from outside partners and creating automated email reports.

Experience

Experience		
Software Engineer, MobileFuse, Waltham, MA	May 2017 – Present	
Maintenance and new features on internal Laravel dashboard project. Creation and launch of new		
Laravel app for automated data ingestion, processing, and email reporting with basic frontend		
incorporating some Vue JS components		
Software Engineer I, Buyerzone, Waltham, MA	Jan 2017 – May-2017	
Added features to internal Yii 1.1 CMS project, work on Symfony 2 application		
Contractor (Software Engineer), Alexander Technology Group (Buyerzone)	August 2016 - Dec 2016	
Performed maintenance tasks on application using internally developed PHP Framework, routine		
DB work in MySQL		
Teaching Assistant, Harvard Extension School CSCI E-15, Cambridge, MA, Part Time	Spring 2016	
This course focuses on developing Dynamic Web Applications with the Laravel PHP framework		
Webmaster, Malden Little League, www.maldenlittleleague.org (inactive)	2016	
Designed and maintain site using the Laravel Framework and MySQL database		
Research Investigator, Millennium Pharmaceuticals, Cambridge, MA, Full Time	2002-2011	
Research Associate, Millennium Pharmaceuticals, Cambridge, MA, Full Time	2001-2002	
Research Associate, BASF, Worcester, MA, Full Time	2000-2001	

Skills

Experience with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL, Oracle, PHP, Laravel Framework

Publications

Identification of a regulatory autophosphorylation site in the serine-threonine kinase RIP2.

DorschM, Wang A, Cheng H, Lu C, Bielecki A, Charron K, Clauser K, Ren H, Polakiewicz RD, Parsons T, Li P, Ocain T, Xu Y. Cell Signal. 2006 Dec; 18(12):2223-9. Epub 2006 May 22.

A selective small molecule IkappaB Kinase beta inhibitor blocks nuclear factor kappaB-mediated inflammatory reponses in human fibroblast-like synoviocytes, chondrocytes, and mast cells.

Wen D, Nong Y, Morgan JG, Gangurde P, Bielecki A, Dasilva J, Keaveney M, Cheng H, Fraser C, Schopf L, Hepperle M, Harriman G, Jaffee BD, Ocain TD, Xu Y.

J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2006 Jun; 317(3);998-1001. Epub 2006 Mar 8.

Education

Degree Candidate, Master of Liberal Arts, Information Technology, Harvard University Extension	2016
School, Cambridge, MA	
Web Technologies Certificate, Harvard University Extension School	2016
Bachelor of Arts, Biochemistry, Brandeis University, Waltham, MA	1996-2000

Community Service

Board of Directors, Information Officer, Malden Little League, Malden, MA

2016

Designed and maintain the Malden Little League website (www.maledenlittleleague.org) and manage the league's online presence.